so good good afternoon folks
and now welcome to our kings of capital
call with
uh with a very special guest deepak
gupta joint managing director
with kotak mahindra bank we also have
the kings of
capital fund manager with us
so let me introduce deepak gupta it's
not always that we have uh
such stars gracing our conference calls
so deepak is the uh is the joint
managing director at kotak uh mahindra
bank he's been there for
29 years uh i think he's worked in
virtually every part of the bank i think
in the 12 years i've lived in india
whenever i've thought about kotak
mahindra bank whenever i thought about
discussing a tricky issue in banking
deepak has been our go to man i think
from compliance to risk
to the credit committee all parts of
banking uh this man is a veteran
i think of his 35 years in banking 29
years deeper
he's been at kotak mahindra bank prior
to that uh he was at
a ferguson would it be right to say uh
deepak a ferguson means you are a
ca right there you claim that fame
right i'm uh mba
at one point of time i used to be an
engineer before okay so so engineer come
mba and now a veteran banker and expert
expert on on on surveilling uh
understanding the indian credit
landscape
so we will come to deepak for his
thoughts on what he makes of the
post-covet world before deepak gives us
his thoughts i'll request
page two to uh just set the scene with
what's happening in indian banking
folks uh we will do a q a with deepak
once deepak's finished uh speaking we'll
do a q a with him
if you have questions keep dropping them
in the q a box
and once deepak's done speaking i'll
take the questions uh we have deeper
till six o'clock so let's make the most
of his time until then
so is over to you to kick things off
thank you sarah so we'll start off with
a background of why we launched
uh the financial services focused fund
kings of capital in july
last year what we had seen till then was
that the previous six seven years
there was a crisis or a challenge every
year
especially for the financial services
sector multiple macro related challenges
which impacted banks and mbfcs largely
whether it be the asset quality review
in 2013 1415 whether it be
uh demonetization introduction of the
gst
after that then there was ilfs crisis
yes bank dhfl crisis so on so forth
as a result of that we saw that npas
for the sector grew uh more than twofold
they all almost tripled over a period of
five six years
uh and this was even before coveted does
uh it was
with this background that
india india saw kuvit come through and
then there was this lockdown for a
period of three four months
because of which there was even more
pressure especially on the weaker banks
weaker nbfcs in the ecosystem
however what we had seen historically
was that high quality lenders gain
market share poster crisis
so uh whether it be the global financial
crisis
whether it be the crisis of the late 90s
early 2000s when 70 percent of india's
nbfcs
uh suffered we saw that it was the high
quality banks high quality nbfcs
who had access to liquidity who had
access to
uh deposits and they were able to absorb
nps irrespective of the magnitude of the
crisis who were able to gain market
share was the crisis
and the reason behind this is that first
of all high quality lenders
have would have been prudent in their
lending practices
even before the crisis hits secondly
they have enough strength on the
liability side of the balance sheet
to not only survive the crisis but also
grow through the crisis
and gain market share post the crisis as
and when the credit demand returns
these high quality banks and nbfcs are
able to gain market share from the
weaker players in the ecosystem
because most competitors would be
struggling with either asset quality
issues
or struggling to raise deposits in the
case of banks struggling to raise
liabilities in the case of nbfcs
the high quality lenders are able to
pick and choose the borrowers of
their liking they are able to price the
risk
according to their liking in the post
crisis era because of which
the net interest margins uh expand was
the crisis because of which
the uh asset quality and the npa ratios
also start normalizing poster crisis
uh as things start normalizing in the
post-crisis era
we also see that pa multiples normalize
as a result of which equity shareholders
tend to gain
uh tend to gain disproportionately and
also get the advantage which
which can be divided into three parts
one is market share gains
second is asset quality improvement and
expansion of names and third is
normalization of pu multiples
what we saw uh what we saw over the past
40 years
is that there is a direct correlation
between
what happens in the u.s and what happens
in india
um and i'll hand it over to sora to take
you through this slide
sure thanks stage so folks uh we've
we've seen this repeatedly in the last
40 45 years america goes into recession
in year t
the dark grey areas are american
recession so 79 to
82 1990 to 92 2000 to 2003
um 2008 nine and and obviously last year
it was an american recession so you see
american recessions in year t
in t plus one the red arrows india's
economy booms right why does that happen
two very simple reasons
a u.s recession gives our country the
two things we need the most
the first is cheap oil the the gray line
the gold
the brown line i'm sorry the brown line
is the
price of oil when the world's largest
consumer of crude goes into recession
the price of oil falls by 50 20 you can
see that
in 91 you can see that in 2000 to 2002
you can see that in 2008 and obviously
you saw that last year
a 50 to 80 drop in the price of oil is a
three percent of gdp boost to india it's
like
god dropping three percent on our
country and we saw that last year right
the government kept the pump price of
petrol the same but they loaded it up
with tax
it gave them a three percent of gdp
fiscal boost which they used to
do the fiscal uh relief that they
announced in august september last year
right
so so simple uh max 50 to 80 percent
drop in the price of oil we get
three percent of gdp boost the second
big uh
uh benefit we get from a us recession is
the blue line the u.s 10-year bond yield
naturally the us 10-year bond deal drops
during a u.s recession typically drops
by two and a half percent
ironically last year dropped exactly by
two and a half percent
when the u.s 10-year bond deal drops uh
in a u.s recession given that oil is
already crushed
the rbi passes on the relief of that uh
drop in the bond deal to all of us
through lower interest rates right
so so everybody on the zoom call uh plus
uh the the our guest banker today were
beneficiaries of this cost of funding
dropped by
two two and a half percent last year and
as a result if you drive around the
streets of indian cities you can see
home loans at six point six percent
uh uh prime prime rated corporates are
borrowing money in the indian bomb
market at four four and a half percent
lowest rates in indian history
so in short a u.s recession gives india
cheap oil and cheap money
u.s recession in year t indian recovery
starts in t plus one
it's played out like a clock work we
were talking about this exactly a year
ago in our webinars back to youth
what we discussed in the earlier slide
so far was
around uh the lending part of our
portfolio
uh so sixty percent of our portfolio
invests in banks and nbfcs
uh and therefore we saw that there was a
major crisis over the past six seven
years
and then there was uh and banks and
ndfc's high quality banks and nbafc's
gain market share poster crisis
the remaining 35 to 40 percent of our
portfolio
is invested in non-lending financials
which is
uh life insurers general insurers asset
managers wealth managers and brokers
now what we've what we saw
and why we have 35 to 40 percent of the
portfolio in non-lending financials is
that india is the only major economy
that around two thousand dollars per
capita income which has only five
percent of household savings in
financial assets
so if we even uh don't compare india to
u.s or some of the european countries
even if we look at south korea or china
or indonesia
all of them have around 30 to 40 to even
50 percent
of household savings in financial assets
uh now if we make conservative
assumption that india goes from five
percent in financial assets to even say
15 percent in financial assets
over the next decade that is about 100
billion
shift to financial assets from real
assets every year
and this is assuming that uh india's
household
wealth does not even increase over the
next 10 years
and we believe that this shift from
physical assets to financial assets will
benefit
uh direct equities mutual funds life
insurers general insurers and of course
money will move to bank deposits uh so
as a result of which we
we believe we've picked the best life
insurers general insurers
asset managers and brokers in our
portfolio will benefit
from this shift towards financial assets
over the next decade
now the way our kings of capital
portfolio companies have
performed over the past five years is
that they've
despite what has happened in the in the
macroeconomic environment
that we discussed they've still given
out 20 to 21 percent earnings
earnings growth whether we look at the
past three years whether we look at the
past five years
and this is along with our return on
equity of 19 to 20 percent
there is a big difference between the
companies in our portfolio versus even
say the bank nifty so twenty percent
uh sort of earnings growth over the past
five years for kings of capital
companies versus seven percent
for the bank nifty 19 return on equity
in fi 20 which was
uh you're where most of the lenders took
gold provisioning in the last quarter
despite that
1920 return on equity versus 10
for the bank nifty
now coming to the larger question which
we get which we are getting
most often right now is uh how have
uh lenders especially lenders in our
portfolio handled covet related stress
the supreme court ruling or not
recognizing nps most of the banks in
nbfcs in our portfolio have
provided well for covert related stress
the reason that they have been able to
do this is the tier 1 ratio
for the lenders in our portfolio is
actually increased year on year
so the tier 1 in q3 f520 this was before
covered was 17
on average for the lenders in our
portfolio
versus 20 as we speak today so despite
covet
there has been a increase by three
percent in the tier one of
the tier one capital of the lenders of
our portfolio
now assuming that the restructuring book
the complete restructuring book is
stressed
assuming that the pro form across npas
will remain as it is even with these
conservative assumptions
the provision coverage ratio for the
lenders in our portfolio
is more than 100 so we believe that more
than 70 80 percent of the stress has
been provided for
whatever is the incremental stress will
come through maybe in the next couple of
quarters
and uh the impact on profitability uh
going forward will not be much
irrespective of
whatever the optical gross nba numbers
will look like
because of the supreme court ruling
and finally coming to growth
how do we go forward on growth how are
the lenders positioned in terms of
capitalizing on
loan demand coming back macro economic
recovery etc
so even in q3 that is a quarter ending
december
we saw that qoq growth was for the
lenders in our portfolio back at four
five percent
so annualized growth was at 17 18
percent we believe that incremental
growth
uh will will come through because most
of the lenders are well positioned
because they have enough
tier one because they have enough
capital and because they have enough
liability strength so they're well
positioned to capitalize on growth
as in when the loan demand growth comes
through
uh they'll come back to 18 20 sort of
growth which we saw on the earlier
slides
so i'll stop here uh and back to you sir
thanks
thank you so so deepak we now hand the
mic over to you metaphorically speaking
would love to hear your thoughts
on what you make of the of this
remarkable post-covert landscape you
guys were the i think you
almost you fired the the starting uh gun
for the market recovery in banking
stocks by doing your qip very early on
i think it was september perhaps right
you know at that time you know we
thought that
you have to survive this pandemic yeah
and
this pandemic will have
a lot of trouble yeah
it's like you're at one shore now and
you have to go to the other shore and
there is a storm brewing
yeah and while you're
you know traversing from this end to the
other because of the storm a lot of your
colleagues around will get into trouble
you have to have
sufficient fuel to cross
so the earlier you take the fuel
hopefully
the more ammunition you have to reach
the other end
but what really happened as it turned
out really is although we started the
whole process
a lot of other people also capitalized
yeah so i think it protected the
industry per se very significantly
in that period of trouble yeah which is
what pages
uh you know graphs really showed and
since
they basically showed two pieces uh
of of uh you know you know the
marketplace one is
the recovery or the collection piece and
the other really is the growth piece let
me just probably
spend a couple of minutes on these two
aspects
really i think when you look at the last
10 months and you go back to
you know the months of april and may
last year
you know it seemed like doomsday
yeah because you know the pandemic had
you know moved very very fast and there
was trouble
all over and at that stage when we all
of us reviewed
our portfolios we said this is a long
term trouble
yeah we said stage one stage two stage
three all of that we said but all of us
thought that it is doomsday all of us
very aggressively estimated
estimated loss let's provide for it yeah
that was our
reaction immediate reaction
as you see the progress over the last
eight ten months and as you sit today
over here what seems real is
it was not as bad as it seemed and and
i'm not talking about the second and the
nth wave which is there but as of now
when you see
look back you realize it's not been as
bad
as it seemed at that point of time yeah
right so
probably there was an overreaction
or like all of us say oh we were
adequately
provided yeah but when you get deeper
into it
the story is not exactly the same
when you get deeper into it and look at
let's say the
three or four broad segments of business
which a financial
entity does you look at the corporate
segment
you look at the sme piece you look at
the agree piece
and you look at the retail piece and
again retail may
there is a secured part of retail and an
unsecured part
the interesting piece really is when you
look at the corporate part
of the lending
yeah it is nowhere near what we thought
it was
all of us by a corporate child corporate
child
i suggest
it is practically close to zero
if i look at a you know zero to ten
scale
on the corporate side it is practically
close to zero
maybe one two thereabouts in terms of
stress in terms of stress terms of
stress
right now you try and think why is it
like that
and one of the things which comes to
mind really and ted showed on his
chart also is a lot of corporates
were already in trouble even before
yeah so the so-called troubled guys were
already out
nice point what was left was relatively
the less troubled guys and even within
this less trouble guys
you know yes the curve the growth curve
was
a sharp k in any case but
all of them were either reasonably
capitalized
or some of the even troubled ones
managed to get fresh equity
you know even the lower part of k curve
guys managed to get fresh equity you
know infrastructure
real estate hospitality a lot of them
picked up equity on the way
or a lot of them you know had sufficient
liquidity
to survive so the corporate side is
close to zero
on the other extreme you have what i
call unsecured retail
whatever we had thought has happened
right it is close to ten at this stage
okay so 10 percent of the unsecured book
is showing stress
no i'm saying the unsecured piece is on
a 0 to 10 scale it's not 10
it's on a 0 to 10 scale if we had
expected x
rate is x incorporate if we had expected
x
it is close to zero yeah and the other
two segments are somewhere
in between so while in average on an
average basis yes it is not as bad
there are no answers to the whole piece
so if i were to sum up on the
recovery collection pieces you know page
was right
it isn't looking as bad as what one had
and hence when you look ahead and by the
way
whatever we had thought of in any case
is adequately provided
yeah so sort of the road ahead seems
pretty clean and clear
yeah and of course i'm caveating it by
saying bye
this discounts the second or third wave
yeah so don't
hold that hold me for that piece as of
now that's hard
when you look at the growth part really
the growth part has been a mixed bag
yeah
and the mixed bag with a lot of
variations
yeah yes like i said it has been
a standard k shape recovery
the upper part of the k curve is still
small
yeah there is still a large part of it
which is
on the lower part of k which means
segments
sectors industries in individual
corporates
which are not out of the woods yet and
when we look at
the marketplace we saw some amount of
see-sawing happening
yeah there is some amount of pent-up
demand which comes to the marketplace
yeah maybe because of a festival or
whatever
some discounts are your end then it
vanishes all over again
so the signal on the growth
side at least at this point of stuff
at this point of time is still guarded
yeah i wouldn't say
you know it is victory yeah it's not a
victory project
sorry yeah it is different so that's
growth and growth we will have to watch
i can hope for the future to be bright
you you speak to anyone and
they will come back with a 10 12 gdp
growth rate going forward
but that's from a you know negative base
yeah when you look at
you know over a two year period you'll
still not end up with
very significant maybe one percent two
percent on a real term
basis so growth is still
caution yeah it is not
over the hill i would say at this point
and within growth
see growth normally happens primarily
two key drivers for growth
yeah one is the working capital growth
from a banker's perspective one is
the standard working capital growth the
second really is growth arising out of
catholics
yeah the second piece is even more
distant
yeah and then i'm not counting let's say
the steel sector or maybe the cement
sector which is doing capex
but those are you know the outliers
steel has had a phenomenal phenomenal
you know all the money which all of them
borrowed in the last six seven months
last month
yeah because they're just throwing up so
much cash yeah so the upper part of k
is doing very well undoubtedly they're
not boring
yeah they're throwing cash up so that's
the dilemma which we have at this point
however
at the macro level while that is how it
is looking
individual entities still have
a reasonable smooth sailing because
when you look at the marketplace the
competitive environment is very
different today
yeah you take a simple thing like home
loans mortgages
you know two years back every tom dick
and harry was out there in the
marketplace
offering you know the lowest to the
lowest you know rate
and it didn't make sense to do business
at those rates
but today it's very different you have
only so many players
yeah and the incremental demand
in some of these segments has come back
with
avengers yeah so
the opportunity basket suddenly
looks bigger because there are only
so few players out there
and that's why the optimism and again
when you look at us
you know about four or five months back
one of the key calls we took really was
you know last
eight nine years we've basically driven
the liabilities part of the game
yeah the library is part of the business
which is
savings deposit customers
and we basically drove it through
a very reasonable savings
interest rate yeah and everything we
drove
around that our entire technology
spends with largely around customer
acquisition for savings products
and that's why today if you look at us
we probably have
the highest casa ratio in the industry
but what we have now see really is since
the comparative environment is
very different and the other interesting
piece for us personally
is the cost of funds is practically the
lowest in the marketplace
and that combination makes it very
attractive for segments which are secure
which are sticky from a customer point
of view
and now you can have good roes
in those businesses so that's the key
driver
so a lot of our strategy is
you know moving from acquiring only
savings customer and and customer
acquisition still is a key part of our
strategy remember because
at the end of the day we are still a
very small bank in the overall
marketplace
to how do i now engage with this
customer
and then when you look ahead all of this
will get driven
and is getting driven increasingly
through technology
because that's just the future
yeah all of us are 50 technologists and
maybe 30 bankers the other 20
is administrators so that's
so those are my quick so there's two
bits really quickly summarize and folks
uh uh keep firing your questions into
that q a box we have
uh deeper until six o'clock so let's
make the most of his of his inputs and
his knowledge
after six o'clock you'll still have
paige and me answering questions on the
portfolio so portfolio related questions
are badminto
let's make the most of deepak gupta's
time till six o'clock
um so i'll quickly summarize uh deepak
what you're saying and then i'll post
the first question
and page if you could just keep curating
from the q a box
for the next few questions so first
point you're saying is
the overall stressed acid picture is
looking much less worrisome now than it
did six months ago when you guys did the
qip
but that overall picture of sort of
comfort hides uh poor polarization you
have a
unsecured retail there is concern
whereas corporate is
sort of sparkling clean right it's
probably the most positive
characterization i've heard on corporate
credit for a long time in india yeah
right so and coming from you that's high
praise for corporate credit quality
uh second layer is you saying you're
talking about growth
and growth payable rio uh that again the
growth picture perhaps is not as
buoyant as perhaps we as investors would
like it to be or perhaps you as a banker
would like it to be but again the
overall picture of less than ideal
buoyancy
on the asset growth side hides a hides a
detail and the detail is
that in several sectors your competition
has withered away
right and specifically we were
discussing housing finance i presume you
mean the
the non-bank part of housing finance
where some of your first while
uh you know aggressive competitors of
two three years ago
are not in the framework anymore which i
guess is what uh
explains the codec bank holdings on the
highways of bombay saying six point
percent cap home loan you're allowing
that to your
your uh sharp drop in cost of
liabilities
over the last couple of years and you're
saying you've got the lowest cost
liabilities in india
and hence amongst the lowest right and
therefore even on that six point six
percent while you're holding many
eastern express highways
point six five yeah
okay
competition really is not enormous at
that at that 6.65 level
whereas i remember june 2017 yeah june
uh there were housing finance companies
issuing cps at six percent
and and therefore then it made no sense
for you
so in that regard uh the consolidation
of market share in your hands
uh is happening albeit beneath the water
line
and all be it in retail rather than
incorporate because
you will gain share but ironically uh uh
through a serendipitous root retailment
you're gaining share yeah
see corporate may share gain connect up
issue for us is slightly
different if you look at us as a bank
on the corporate side we are present
practically everywhere where we are
comfortable
to be present yeah
and in all of these places
our exposure currently is where i would
say
close to what the appetite is
and the question really is do i increase
my appetite in some of these places
given what i look ahead or no it's not
about acquiring new customers
we are there everywhere so if you look
at corporate abcdefg
wherever we want to be there we are
there so do i want to take
thousand crores more in corporate a
our clients as questions with with with
your with what you've said so far
so let's start with corporate nice place
to start happy note to start
you're seeing corporate credit quality
surpass your expectations
steel companies right steel companies
are coming in repaying
that is the level of corporate uh credit
quality we are seeing
in the same time the public sector banks
in our country right so they are maxed
out
right and surely therefore the next two
three four years
is the time for yourself and perhaps a
couple of other private sector banks
to clean up uh on the corporate side and
build us a
you know three four player duopoly
constructing corporate lending credit
quality
application you've got tier one the qip
was beautifully timed
opposition psu bank competition
withering on the vine
isn't this the time to go for it on the
corporate side
yes it makes sense except for two
caveats really one is
remember at the higher quality
end of the corporate spectrum
no bank will let go even if it is
within quotes unprofitable yeah because
those are your priced customers so you
don't normally
uh let go very easily
the second issue of course is what i
call
risk at it see at the end of the day
from
a banker's perspective concentration
risk is an extremely important
risk parameter and we value that
extremely because you know you have
found over the last 20 years
in a year's time things change and they
change
very fast so someone
or a carpet which looks very nice today
may not necessarily be the same
you know even a year later or two years
later and
you may end up taking sort of three or
five years
exposures at this point of time and you
know corporates themselves have been
very smart
interest rates have come down to you
know rock bottom
yeah so all of them have sort of swapped
their older debts uh with low cost and
longer 10 years
both ways so you you
at this point may run the risk of you
know
lending long so you are mismatched at
one end at a low cost really
and locked in for a longish period of
time
but having said that underlying of what
you're saying is
right there will be significant
opportunities
within the broad framework of you know
concentration after that
take it now let's just look at the
retail piece right so
so retail lending in india right um
uh clearly over time uh the the public
sector enterprises while
they'll probably cling on to the retail
books incremental growth in the psu's
retail books
is gonna is gonna dwindle and the
question then becomes
uh if you had to look out say five years
out ten years out
will we see that housing finance or a
lap or perhaps even unsecured retail
will that become a three-four private
sector bank dominated sector
or will it stay in the current highly
fragmented
uh format where you know 100 and bfcs
are also doing retail
uh 30 psus are also backing it out in
retail and every private sector bank is
doing written do you see consolidation
and retail
so so you know for retail the way i'd
look at it is
i broadly break it up into two parts
yeah
one is what i call secured retail
and the other is what i call unsecured
retail
now secure retail by nature is
safer yeah and normally something like a
mortgage
so is a pretty sticky product
just because he will not
run away however the problem on secured
retail
still largely for us really is it still
has a very frictioned process
register office register
there is a physical element which is not
digitizable easily it will probably
happen
it's happening parts of it are happening
but it's still
not friction free
the unsaturated part on the other hand
is increasingly becoming friction free
and digitized so on the secured side
the competition still will require
physical
presence advantages
on the unsecured side it will move to
digital and the competition will not
just be
banks or financial services firms it
will be the fintechs
it will be the ecom guys and we have to
watch out for
all of them really but on the secured
part it probably will
still be restricted amongst banks and
some nbfcs
right page over to you yeah
if you were to look at uh kovit as a
crisis uh
where would you say we are today if you
were to compare it to the past 20 25
years
uh is it comparable to say the global
financial crisis
or would we say we are it's a two
thousand three four sort of mode where
we can see a lot of uh recovery has
already
already come through and the next three
four years uh we'll see
a strong sort of growth coming through
we are already at on an interest rate
but
from interested perspective at a low
which is similar to 2003
uh from a recovery perspective maybe we
are where we were in 2009-10
um where would you say we are right now
each of them is a different set of
circumstances
yeah this time round
very different from last few times like
i said
two things one is provisioning seems to
be
reasonably adequate
b unlike the last round the corporate
segment
touchwood up to now has been pretty good
if you see trouble and stress
whether it was the 2000 you know eight
nine time
or you look at the 99 2000 time or the
2003 2004
stress always came big time
from the carpet side
yeah and again i'm saying touchwood this
time round it doesn't look
like that and b
fortunately all of us
have sort of planned in advance and
provided
in the last few rounds the provisioning
and the hits happened later on
yeah here all of us maybe in his i don't
know possible
we're sort of pre-prepared
and it wasn't as bad as what we had
expected so it's been different this
time now
and hence if macro growth comes back
i suspect recovery will be much faster
because you know one is your fighting
recovery
b is array by i have you know accounted
for it it is provided for
let me move ahead with life and get on
to growth
so it's it's more of that kind this time
rather than the past so
you know the extent of trouble may be
relatable to the previous times
but the circumstances gives a far more
optimistic proposition at this point so
there was never a bad
there's never a good time for things
like covet to happen but if you ever
said
i can time it as a banker you would have
said vocal corporate
stress cycle bitcoin
and then you see that it's a fortunate
timing from that point
right so so it's actually a very nice
insight that covet could not have a time
better from a corporate stress cycle in
our country
so i've got two questions related
questions actually from different people
on your liabilities franchise
both are sort of uh grudging admiration
while a question
so narendra shaji asks you know how come
kotak can do
these six percent wala
and still say that our cost of funds is
the lowest in the country so that's
one question on liabilities
he asks he says i'm both a customer and
an investor and kotak
was it not possible in co
in in packets was it not possible for
management to get some sense of stress
when you raised capital but at the low
price of
1100 so he's saying could you not get
some do some maths and says
so one is on the equity side of
liability on the your
uh your sa piece how can you pull off
the miracle so
i think the first one is a simple one
yeah ultimately remember
it is how you look at it you can say bye
mera saree chay percentage
char person here but what happens really
is
you're growing your deposit base very
fast
so the comparison is not with the four
percent of
someone else the comparison shifts to
incremental money is it coming at six
percent
or incremental money i have to borrow in
the form of term deposit
is it coming at seven percent so the way
you have to look at it is
the incremental money is coming at a
lower cost
don't get carried away by just the six
percent on saha
because the six percent
you know converts into a casa of
close to sixty percent
someone else at a four percent sa may be
at a casa
forty percent so i have a much
higher share of low cost deposits
which means my incremental deposits
which i have to borrow at a higher cost
which are typically term deposits
is that much lesser yeah if you do a
simple math
you will realize that 40 percent have 4
percent and the balance sixty percent at
seven percent or sixty percent at six
percent and by the way it is not six
all through yeah six is only in in in
the lowest market
and the remaining forty percent at a
higher cost
you will arrive at a simple logic
so we look at it as savings from term
deposit because that is what you are
saving when your kasa is so high
it would not be the same as the casa our
kasa was also at 40 percent
so we have a much higher percentage of
low cost deposits so we need to
borrow lesser of higher cost deposits
that's the way
that's why you can justify six percent
and you know there is a very interesting
phenomenon and i call it
the fight between the heart and the mind
a deposit customer particularly a
savings deposit customer is
what i call a lifetime acquisition
then he's comfortable he's a very you
know high inertia customer
he will not run away because you know
liability side of a bank's business is
business of the heart
he likes you he trusts you he's
comfortable with your mobile banking app
he finds it very convenient all of that
the customer does not move around the
asset customer
someone who takes a you know a personal
loan from you or a credit card from you
comes from the mine or a car loan
operates from the mind he's not coming
from the heart
he will shop around
he will go from there on the liability
side customers
you know rely a lot more on softer
aspects of finance rather than the tough
interest aspect so for example we don't
offer six
now we are practically at 375
but it doesn't mean customers have
walked away
yeah so that's the first one the second
one is a difficult one you see at that
point of time
when you looked around like i said
it looked like doomsday yeah and then
you know one of the
philosophies which we as a firm have
always prophesied really
is protect capital
yeah and be adequately protected
so it is safer for you to run
with comfortable capital rather than
start running for capital
later on and like i said one of the big
opportunities we saw at that point of
time is
a ship has to move from this shore to
that
and there is a storm and in this storm
there will be other ships there are
other ships some of them will
fail and there will be opportunity for
you
to acquire them so be
tanked up with capital so that if
those opportunities do come you can
you know go in for those opportunities
of course like i said after that
everyone
started raising capital so the
opportunity basket got limited
so the second one is a position which
you take at a point of time based on
circumstances
you know with hindsight it may look yes
why did you
raise capital at that price but that's
the call at that point of time you will
be right sometime and
not necessarily looking at the bright
side looking on the right side
one of our mortal fears in marcellus
when we launched the kings of capital
portfolios page figured out
and he lovely chart for our clients that
jb kotak banker kyp
that's the top of the capital market
cycle right
so we're so glad that you got the qip
out of the way so early in the cycle
this time
page over to you so one of the questions
is related to
what we discussed one of the clients is
asked whether
so now that all the large private sector
banks have enough capital enough tier
one
will there be consolidation of banks in
the sense
of acquisitions um because the
government's also started
to show signs of divesting psu banks
is there a possibility that say a kotak
or one of the banks
acquires one of these banks
well it is a possibility yeah i'll
see ultimately it's a combination of
several factors yeah
first the economics has to be right yeah
when i mean economics
really means what are you acquiring at
what price
that's extremely important i think the
second thing which people forget and
we've been through it
so i can really comment on it
fitment is extremely important cultural
thinking
yeah very very important yeah otherwise
you end up wasting
two to three years post combination or
merger
in just trying to fight that battle and
you lose very critical time in the
marketplace
yeah and of course the third one really
is at the end of the day
which probably is related to the first
one of economic study is
what are the pluses and what are the
minuses you know at this
stage when we look at
it ourselves we
need a lot of customers because like i
said we are still a very small bank
so the opportunity for customer
acquisition is high
the opportunity for geographical
presence is not very
so you will not be willing to pay too
much for
geography but you will be willing to pay
significantly for customers yeah and
that's what will
drive the economies basketball
so i wouldn't say it is a clear s or a
clear no i think it needs to be
evaluated
and there will be takers undoubtedly of
course
deeper if you leave aside the specifics
of whether uh
kotak buys a psu bank or not do you
reckon the next
10 years will see further consolidation
in the indian banking sector will it see
further fragmentation
in the indian banking sectors new new
guys come in
i think the the fragmentation
mix will be different when i look ahead
okay it may not necessarily
be the same kind of people who you have
out there i think it will probably be
a much more very different place
yeah so i suspect fragmentation
but uh a very different means so
so i suppose one scenario that we keep
thinking of is four or five giant banks
lots on purana private sector banks and
so on
but sort of you know what is banking
we are increasingly coming to you know
that belief what is banking itself will
change
it may not be this way
it may be very different and this tech
world and then we are very watchful of
it really
is a very different ballgame what a bank
of tomorrow will
be and look like can be very different
from what it is today
so so so it's a little interesting
subject and you know uh that prompts me
to ask something
uh neither in the western world nor in
say
places like singapore which are fairly
high tech places
um not indeed in china
have we seen uh tech disrupt banking in
the sense of
lending money
fintech as a forward business activity
hasn't yet become
uh prevalent in any economy including
economies far more
technologically sophisticated than ours
right similarly
barring say taobao in china uh we
haven't seen
the liability part of banking also being
taken up aggressively
so for example uber advisories uh online
asset managers etc
right so so this perpetual notion that
banking as we know it could be disrupted
by
tech have you guys seen real sort of
um cogent concrete examples
of where tech has come in disrupted the
traditional model of banking no
one hasn't seen it but i don't think
that should
you know make us okay you know lose our
god
yeah or lower our god you know it's like
what we keep talking about
[Music]
i am like a vacuum cube i can keep
improving i can keep adding some
buttons here improving the glass quality
but if i have not prepared for
the transistors
it will happen fast and sudden right
will be a c they are binary shift
it's a binary shift what are we banking
on today we're banking on
a trust yeah because that drives a lot
of the liability
piece and b
a protection due to regulation
there are regulated entity yeah and and
there is an element of protection which
happens out of that in the financial
services
but both these paradigms can change very
fast
yeah you know for a long time for
example we'd say
kali payment you know he will never get
customers
taken you know all my customers on the
payments platform but
bulk of his money is still with us but
some of those are changing
because they have trust builds up over a
period of time yes it doesn't change
overnight
but you cannot say the same thing three
years later
and then all of us are very vigilant and
you know care careful about and then
worried to some extent
about this piece so the way banking gets
done itself
may be very different tomorrow in three
years time in five years time
right and that's why back again whether
it is a disintegrated form
or a very highly integrated tech form
who knows
right so couple of questions from our
clients who are hungry for growth as you
can make out the marcellus client is
like the ipl generation
so so rohan says that look you're saying
you've got the lowest cost of
liabilities
uh yet hdfc bank which is five times
bigger than you is growing faster than
you so
you know please help me understand that
and then abhi abhijan gives a
helpful sort of hint he's saying that
ibc is therefore surely
the indian promoter or the the
institutional safeguards have improved
our promoters behaving more responsibly
and if i joined the two up
uh lowest cost of funds one-fifth the
size of hdfc bank
ibp improved behavior on promoters
is there a is there a faster a faster
loan book growth ahead for kotak in the
years
in the years ahead yeah no
you see again this is something which i
keep mentioning
i have money in my pocket doesn't mean
that i will stand on marine drive and
say bye lake a job
because that is activity one of a banker
it has to come back yeah and
how much ever i may want by pura
jeff capes unless
i'm conscious and cognizant of
the risk yeah
it is of no use and repeatedly
once every three years five years you
see
you know markets keep coming back and
giving you that lesson all over again
it's not that we're scared of pressing
the acceleration
yeah but it's not going to be an
unbridled
by cello cost of fun kamehameha
because you know ultimately you must
remember
the banking equation is a very funny
equation
opportunity to lose is 100
so you know you have to be wrong one in
50 times for that equation to
yeah get into trouble yeah so risk
is an extra extremely important
parameter yeah
and yes i understand risk
and hence while the you know the foot
on the accelerator is pressed i have to
have the second foot
continuously ready and you know cost
of fund is an opportunity to
enter better quality yes
yeah because as you move you know you
know up
the quality curve the customer demands
you
a lower cost so that there is always
a good equation but it doesn't mean
unbridled
growth and again you know again from
personal experience
i can tell you the moment when growth
starts veering above the 30
and there's not overall in segments
in some segments it comes back
and starts haunting you two to three
years later
because at the end of the day there are
processes there are people there is
technology
when you grow beyond a certain amount
some of that does keep
coming back at you and of course you've
got to correct it there
right
you've got multiple business lines
multiple businesses within kotak
life insurance general insurance wealth
brokerage uh even special situations so
out of
all of these businesses which do you
think is the same most promising one or
how do you
think about allocating capital uh to
each of these businesses
uh looking forward well you you know you
are asking a parent
the other person see it's it's tough to
do that choice but you know sitting
where we are at this point of time
the spectrum looks very interesting
because you take a segment
and in the marketplace a our share is
very small b
the market opportunity for growth is
huge you know you showed that graph now
two thousand dollars you know and 100
billion
incremental you look at each and every
segment you look at life insurance you
look at general
insurance you look at brokerage take a
segment
it is insignificant you take unsecured
personal loans
so i think it's very difficult to choose
yeah
and then and hence you know yeah
while mr mukherjee says you know
declutter
isolate focus
at this point of time a lot of it looks
good
so don't ask me to choose favorites
please
it's pretty much good and
the good news is the whole still makes a
lot more sense than
each individual part
sorry you asked the second one which i
missed page
there was a second part was there a
second question you asked
no this was the question okay so deep
boxing got four minutes let's address
the
the sort of the most topical question
across the world
a lot of people apparently can see the
future they believe that as the covert
vaccinations sort of
play out in economic activity will
resume
there's all this garage bar trillion
dollar fiscal and monetary stimulus
inside the global economy so stimulus
powered customers with their covet jabs
will go berserk
now you guys i'm sure uh uh have a
fairly you know uh acute sense for risk
he just gave a
lovely way to think about risk in
banking what do you make of this whole
notion that higher inflation and higher
interest rates
means that the party will come to an end
so you know uday had a very simple
answer
just a couple of days back trying to
talk of this inflation he said
we've been hearing from 2008 2009 the
wolf is coming
the wolf is coming the wolf is coming
yeah and then all economists have said
hey this is the theoretical
uh you know logical way you know so much
liquidity
so much acid bubble it must happen it
must happen
it's not happening does it mean that
it won't happen no it won't it doesn't
mean that
does it mean that i must not have my you
know guards on
i must have my guards on yeah
but if i start looking very inflation
[Music]
yeah then i'm not in business soon
yes i must have my risk management on
to think of an eventuality if suddenly
inflation shoots up to
seven eight percent tomorrow it's quite
possible theoretically
it should have happened yeah or it must
happen in the next
3 to 6 to 12 months but
you know it's such a complex equation
today
it's not just dependent on two or three
parameters so
the brighter and the optimistic way to
look at it is
yeah don't worry about it too much
yeah we're looking at a growth
environment just now even if you look at
a 10 12 percent
gdp growth and part percent inflation
why assad percent
you're talking about 15 odd percent you
know nominal
growth going forward and banking
must be a multiple of that so be happy
with that prepare for that
but keep your risk i mean i mean like i
said don't stand on marine drive and
throw money
yeah be prepared for this keep
evaluating those risks
but it's probably not
at this point of time looking like an
issue
so thank you deepak i think one of the
main reasons we are so keen you speak to
our
our client base and our audiences we
keep getting exhorted by people
to invest in lenders some bankers some
nbfcs
who specialize in standing in marine
drive and and throwing out notes
uh as being the middle class folks we
obviously don't have the nerve to do
that
uh but people don't sort of like
listening from hearing it from us and
that's why when
stalwarts like you explain if you get it
wrong you lose hundred percent you get
it right you make two percent
and i was thinking you can lose hundred
percent with underlying debt equity of
10x so then you're gone it's bankrupt so
so question is to compound consistently
for our clients
with bankers who don't stand on marine
drive uh uh
but instead sit in the office doing risk
management and also
bankers who come on our on our calls
with the marcellus clients thank you
very much
we learned a lot and thanks for all the
pleasure pleasure
and thank you thank thank you sir thank
you paige and thank you
everyone else yeah bye have a good day
thanks people thank you very much
bye-bye people thank you so folks now we
move to the
the q a uh for clients with uh with the
marcellus team
what i'll do is the last stage to kick
off with the
most uh frequently asked questions on
kings of capital right we've been now
live since july so we obviously got a
sense what are the things most clients
ask
uh so vintage will take us through the
faq as he does that feel free to punch
in more questions
and then this time i will take the
questions and fire it at page
and he'll he'll try his best to answer
your queries and questions on kings of
capital
we are managing now i think 350 360
crores
uh you'll see the compounding in a
minute but over to youth
yeah so looking at most of the questions
that we've got
so far can be
split into four three or four broad
headings one is why invest in a
portfolio which consists of
only one sector companies from only
financial services
um uh why invest in a portfolio of
companies would be far more volatile
than other portfolios given that
it's only financial services what is the
outcome of investing at a time like this
when nifty is near its all-time high or
at an all-time high
and what is the impact of investing in
lenders which have high price to book
multiples so we'll cover off
these three four questions in the coming
few slides
the first question on why invest in a
portfolio which consists of
only banks and bfc is non-lending
financials that is
only one sector so what we did uh uh
look at was over the past 20 years if we
only compare
bank nifty with the nifty so this is no
stock selection this is a comparison of
the two indices
we looked at the the returns first so
return undoubtedly
the bank nifty over the past 20 years is
given 23
on a one year rolling basis versus 14
percent
for the uh nifty so even at an index
level there is a big difference
uh 23 percent gigger versus 14 gig or so
difference of nine percent
on a one year rolling return three basis
secondly when we looked at the sharp
ratios
because uh the biggest biggest
sort of argument against a portfolio of
financial services is that will be
highly volatile
so we looked at sharp ratios for the two
indices
uh and we saw that the bank nifty
outperforms the nifty uh by more than 60
the sharp ratio for the bank nifty is
1.6 times that of the nifty
um and this is data over the past 20
years this is a comparison of the two
indices
secondly how many times has the nifty
delivered a negative return in a quarter
so we've seen that in 41 percent of
cases nifty delivers a negative return
in a quarter this is data for the past
20 years this is not a short period of
time
versus 35 for the bank nifty uh
how many times has it been the case that
in three consecutive quarters as the
nifty delivered a negative return
so this is this has been the case in 14
percent
uh over the past 20 years versus only
five percent for the bank nifty
so only three of the past 81 quarters as
the bank nifty delivered
a negative return versus uh
in 11 cases for the nifty
so three times higher probability for
the nifty to deliver a negative return
in three consecutive quarters
versus the bank nifty so at an index
level we see that first of all
the sharp ratio is 1.6 times higher for
the bank nifty
secondly number of times you deliver
negative return
is much lower for the bank nifty and
thirdly even if you look at consecutive
quarters of negative returns it's been
uh it's occurred only four times in the
past for the bank nifty versus eleven
times for the nifty
uh so to even look at
the recent three four five years uh even
if you look at the past two years when
we saw lfs yes bank kovaid
uh uh dhfl etc even during those two two
and a half years the bank nifty has
outperformed the nifty
um so when we talk about the recent two
three years when we've seen covid
uh maybe the past year is what colors
have judgment
but the past two to two and a half to
three years even during this time period
the bank nifty as an index
has outperformed the nifty uh coming to
the question on
what is the sort of volatility for high
quality lenders versus high quality
non-financial companies
now what we did was we looked at
companies which had
uh delivered consistent historical
fundamentals that is
a consistent return capital employed of
more than 15 percent consistent growth
of more than
10 revenue growth of more than 10 for
every year over the past 10 years
and we created 10 such portfolios
starting from
2000 to 2010. for each of these
portfolios
we also created a portfolio of such
financial companies
that is loan book growth of more than 15
percent for each of the previous 10
years
and roe of more than 15 percent for each
of the preceding 10 years
now for each of these 10 portfolios what
we observed was
that every time uh in each and every
case
the sharp ratio of the high quality
lenders of the high quality financial
companies
was higher than the sharp ratio of the
high quality non-financial companies
so in 100 of cases we saw higher sharp
ratios
even more surprisingly what we saw was
in seven of the eleven portfolios the
standard deviation itself
for the financial companies was lower
than the non-financial companies
therefore when it comes to high quality
lenders
and high quality lenders when we compare
them to high quality non-financial
companies
the volatility itself is lower so for a
hdfc bank for a kotec bank
the volatility will be lower than most
of the non-financial high quality
non-financial companies
and when we combine these two factors
first at an index level itself
you are written advantage because your
sharp ratio is higher
second layer of second layer of
higher outperform and higher sharp
ratios is that when you select high
quality financial companies
you get an even higher sharp ratio than
high quality non-financial companies
moving forward on this notion of what
happens if we invest when the nifty is
at an
all-time high or the bank nifty is at an
all-time high what we did was we took
the case of a very unlucky investor who
invest
exactly when the nifty hits an all-time
high so
and we took the five stocks which have
been listed from kings of capital over
the past 20 years
and every time the nifty hits an
all-time high the investor invests
in this five stock portfolio uh and what
we saw was
that in more than 95 percent cases in 98
cases we saw that the five-year return
is more than fifteen percent
in more than seventy percent cases the
five-year return is more than twenty
percent
so irrespective of when you invest
because the share price
because the earnings compounding book
value per share compounding is so strong
the share price share price keeps on
compounding at more than fifteen percent
more than twenty percent
and that makes the price to book
multiple or the be multiple
almost redundant and
uh finally coming to uh the impact of
entry price to book multiples on your
eventual returns
so we did an exercise where we saw that
how much
of share price returns of an investor
can be attributable to entry price to
book multiples
so what we found out was as long as you
have a long time horizon
which is greater than say three years
five years seven years
uh less than twenty percent of your
returns will be driven by change in
price to book multiples
over a period of time say if if we take
a scenario of
say 15-year time horizon 95 percent of
share price returns will be driven by
book value per share compounding and
that is the essence of investing in high
quality lenders
we need to focus on something which
drives more than 85 90 percent of values
value share price returns and not the
remaining 10 15 20 percent
uh this is the performance inception uh
we've delivered
about uh 32 since inception in the kings
of capital portfolio
uh 60 of the portfolio consists of
lenders 40 percent consists of
non-lenders uh the lenders in our
portfolio have delivered about 51
percent since inception
and we've launched in july so it's been
about seven eight months now
current aum stands at around 350 360
crores
so folks i'll kick off with those
questions on
uh the under performance right as you
can see the under performance is a
statistical thing
the nifty banks index by definition is
all banks
and as stage is saying our banks have
also done
if you adjust for the cash drag because
remember
in six months this portfolio is built up
to 350 crores there's
relentless flow of cash into the
portfolio which creates cash drag
adjusting for that our banks have more
than kept up with the
with the bank nifty uh so one of you
is saying why don't you use nifty
financial services posh nifty financial
services is also 90
lenders so whether anybody likes it or
not whether we like it or not
there is no index in india which has
60 lenders 40 non-lenders and we don't
we don't have a problem with that it's
just that the regulator requires us to
have a
benchmark we've given bank nifty as a
benchmark honestly if a client has a
problem with uh
32 returns since 28 july uh uh you know
we would
love not to have that client uh our our
goal is to consistently compound for our
clients and
and from the day we started kings of
capital i was investor number one it's
consistently compounding and
it's done exactly what it says on the
train and you can also see hopefully
after talking to the people gupta today
you can also see why it's consistently
compounding right we are invested in
clean high quality lenders with uh
with strong comparative advantages the
explained that the cost of funds is now
the lowest in the country
and workers were steadily growing the
business no drama no adventure
we link we lock ourselves into such
companies and we compound that
at good rates if anybody has a problem
with 32 percent compounding in six
months this is raw compounding folks
this is not
come this is not uh annualized right if
you have problem with 32
compounding please don't come to
marcellus
now let's focus on stocks so there's a
question on avastage uh
one client i just lost it in the list of
questions i forget the name and see
amit is asking amit khanna is asking he
said that
deepak jesus said retail business is in
distress you know you have
uh avas in the portfolio how do you
justify that
yeah so i was uh if we uh
link back our discussion if you go back
to the discussion with uh
it's on the secured side of retail
100 percent of ours loan book is secured
they do granular small ticket size
housing loans
in tier 3 tier 4 sort of cities
in india average ticket size of around
eight nine lakh rupees
and avas has been doing this first as uh
as a subsidiary of au
um he started off as a subsidy of a you
then au bank
you became a bank um and therefore they
had to sell off their stake to
uh the private equity players who own
ours now
and in housing finance uh like even
deepak gupta was mentioning
currently there is a strong resurgence
of demand
there is more than enough demand in
housing finance and there are
not many players who are able to cater
to that demand because most of the
housing finance companies over the past
five years suffered massively
awas on the other hand over the past
five years has had enough liquidity has
never
borrowed money in the cpa market as a
tier one capital of more than 50 percent
and it does not do developer loans it
does not do
a high ticket 50 lakh one crore or be a
ticket size sort of lots what it does is
it lends to uh it lends directly to
people who are building their own home
it does not lend to people who it does
not lend to properties which are under
construction even
and it lends to these people directly in
tier three tier four cities
at twelve thirteen fourteen percent uh
when its cost of funds is around seven
eight percent so it's making five
percent spreads
because of its ability to underwrite
credit in
rural areas where most banks and ndfcs
are not able to underwrite this this
sort of credit and it is able to do so
because of its
uh because of its links to au small
finance bank
which also follows a similar business
model of
uh lending to the self-employed lending
to the self-employed by
assessing credit on the basis of cash
flow rather than any other formal income
proof
and therefore it has historically been
able to maintain asset quality across
npas of under one percent
okay so so there's a question on you
know you
do you have a small mid cap
uh so anonymous attendee asks can you
know can you let us know if you have any
small cap or mid cap lenders
amongst your eight lenders and how do
you select amongst non-market
non-market leaders amongst these small
caps
right uh yes so we do have
like we discussed davas we do have a
couple of
other smaller banks one small bank one
small nbfc
and the process of selecting these
lenders
is simple that the process is what we've
illustrated
uh in the past as well first of all we
eliminate companies which are poor
accounting quality
we run all of these banks and ndfcs
through our forensic filter
we have a set of 11 accounting ratios
specifically designed for banks and
ndfcs
about a third about 35 to 40 percent
of the 100 stocks in our universe get
eliminated by way of our forensic filter
itself
the next level of filtering is whether
these banks and nbfcs have historically
been able to
uh been able to generate a return on
capital employed or return on equity
above cost of equity or not
uh that is the second level of filter
again about 30 35 companies get
eliminated
at this stage of the filtering process
and then we are left with about 25 30
companies where we try and assess what
is the sort of competitive advantage
that these companies have and what has
what has been the reason behind the
consistently high returns on equity so
all banks or ndfcs that we have
consistently have
first of all tier one above 15 16
percent
and decent returns on equity above 15 16
so angel gupta asks a question if most
of the stocks in this portfolio
is public information could you please
comment
what advantage we as investors get by
taking help of marcellus
yeah so there are two three uh two three
aspects to this
one is uh the position sizing
so position so apart from stock
selection position sizing itself
uh is is what leads to
uh returns which can be pretty different
even with the same set of stocks
so if we would have held a portfolio of
uh which would have an equal weights
across all our stocks especially in
kings of capital
so across our 12 stocks we have one
stock which is at 15 16
uh in the portfolio and we have one
stock which is at three and a half four
percent in the portfolio um and that
sort of divergence would eventually
result in very different results if you
were to build a portfolio of the same
1213 stocks uh with either equal weights
or weights which you would you would
assign to the stocks on your own
so one is position sizing the other is
there will always be elements
of risks risk
working for example how do you think
about succession planning at most of
these companies
how do you think about the impact of
succession planning at
hdfc bank and how do we how do we keep
on adjusting for that in our portfolios
either by way of position sizing or
maybe by
we have completely exit exiting or
entering new stocks
so for example we had one stock which we
exited from the portfolio in the past
seven eight months
now how do we take that call of exiting
dcb bank
and which new stock do we get into the
portfolio
so these are the calls which will lead
to eventually different sort of outcomes
even in share price performance over a
period of time
so folk stage is too modest to say this
himself so i'll say it on his behalf
so just to give you a sense of how
powerful position sizing is
so back in um first april early april
bajaj finance was i remember around
three percent of the ccp portfolio
consistent compartment
remember kcp only started in in july so
back in april 2020 with the covet panic
on at full throttle
bajaj finance had corrected by 70
and it was at uh three percent of our
portfolio
uh these led the effort which uh uh
which led the team to conclude that
bajaj finance on 15th april 2020
is an even stronger franchise than it
was on first january 2020
and therefore by late april we told our
trader to triple our position in bajaj
finance right and
those of you who are ccp clients would
have made a lot of money on the back of
that call to triple by
finance so that sort of work right where
the rest of the country is panicking
uh saying finance or this broker that
broker is putting cell call right
to do the research to keep uh to stay
calm
execute uh triple the position tandem
that's the skill that we bring to the
table these talks that we hold the
reason we make them public
is these are well-known stocks anyway if
somebody did a little bit of work they
would find out any way marcellus holds
it we are happy to therefore talk about
what we hold
we're happy to tell you why we do it
what we don't disclose to the public is
not only the position size at a point in
time we also don't disclose
where are we ramping up where are we
ramping down and through that ramp up
ramp down through position sizing
we make a lot of money for our clients
and we hope to continue doing that for
many years to come
let's move to another subject which is i
think very
appropriate very relevant for people
like us abhijen
asks about how do you deal with key man
risk
right you know you're investing in
companies where one or two people are
very central to that franchise
what happens to that to that what
happens if that person
dies how does marcellus deal with that
yeah so to give some more insight on the
way we
first of all stock selection is what we
explained uh
to give some more insight on how we
adjust for our how we position size
basis schema and risk succession
planning
and also what the company is doing on a
continuous ongoing
basis so one part is getting the stock
into the portfolio
uh and the and then the second part is
whether the company is doing enough
uh on an ongoing basis to keep up its
competitive advantage
and to keep competition out and
therefore able is the company
in the future as well going to
sustainably generate returns and equity
available cost of equity
so across all all stocks in our
portfolio and across all portfolios of
marcellus
we have a couple of frameworks to
uh to decipher whether a company is
well positioned for succession planning
whether a company
is doing enough to maintain its
competitive edge to maintain its
competitive advantage on an
ongoing basis or not now the way we look
at succession planning is there are
three
three factors on which we score
companies on succession planning
one is uh how strong is how strong and
how independent is the board
are there people who are related to the
promoter or people who are related to
the ceo and the management of the board
or is the board truly independent as
people from diverse fields
who can help the management team give an
independent point of view
and help them with the business second
is
since how long have most of the key men
says the cfo the ceo most of the people
who've been with the company
for a long period of time and are in
prominent positions how long have they
been with the company
does the company have to recruit people
from outside the organization on a
regular basis
or have they been elevated from within
the company
and finally third is what is the sort of
decentralization and what sort of
processes are in place at the company
so basis these three factors we try and
assess what is the risk of succession
planning at a company
um and how do we position size that
company in our portfolio
okay so there's a couple of house
squeaking housekeeping questions i'll
quickly address
so anurag shukla asks lately you have
trimmed bajaj from my ccp but left it
untouched in my kcp any reason
simple reason anuragji we are adding a
stock in your
ccp we are adding a davakidar monopolist
in your ccp portfolio i suspect rakshit
will talk about it in the
in the webinar he does it does in next
month
where he'll explain to you which
monopolist is being added to your
ccp portfolio um and to make space for
that we had to reduce your bajaj by a
little bit
um we have had no change in our
conviction in bajaj and therefore it
continues to be in all our portfolios
um uh shankar brahma asks is marcellus
looking at uh
amid small cap ems in the near term i'm
sorry zankar know the answer is we're
not gonna be
uh launching any mid small cap pmss in
the coming fiscal
uh we might reopen little champs to
some flows in 2022
perhaps you know some still middle of
the year 2022 late
2022 we might open little champs for a
fair fresh infusion flows but uh no
plans for
small mid cap ems in the current at the
coming fiscal
right uh let's move to another uh a
subject which is
which is a thing very interesting so
nirvani asks will you
be keen to add position stage in
exchanges registrars custodians
to play the savings angle
we've looked at we've looked at some of
the custodians we've looked at some of
the market infrastructure plays
in the past and when we are building the
portfolio as well and we continue to
look at them
but the challenge with most of them is
that the competitive edge
or the competitive advantage that they
have is given by
either the government or the regulator
and that at any given point of time
can be can be taken away by the
regulator so
for the regulator to allow these
companies to consistently make
25 return on equity or 20 30 25 30
percent return on capital employed
uh will be very difficult as soon as the
regulator or the government sees that
they are making return on capital
employed or return on equity above
cost of capital uh there will be some
either regulatory change
or there will be a new player which will
come in
and that will again come down to cost of
capital therefore we are a bit hesitant
on adding
any of these market infrastructure plays
to the to the portfolio
uh so there's a quite an interesting
idea
svs chauhan has suggested uh he's saying
perhaps he's saying apologies it's
difficult for me to make out the gender
sphen is saying can you not split and
show the percentage growth for
lenders and non-lenders so i suspect
what what they're referring to is
when we show performance can we not show
lenders right so that this whole you
know this whole notion
that casey
we're not that fast about what people
think of our performance at many levels
but it's a neat idea you know anything
which gives clients more visibility
more transparency will think about it so
thank you for that sps john
that's a neat idea we'll think about it
um sudarangani asks
for those who have not entered the kcv
portfolio is it a tad too late to enter
now
yeah i'll share the slides just a second
yeah so if you look at this slide what
we have shown over here
is uh irrespective of the price to book
multiple you enter at
irrespective of the multiple you enter
at
uh more than eighty percent of share
price returns
over the next five years 10 years or 15
years will be driven by
book value per share compounding so as
long as
we are convinced of the fact that
hdfc bank codec bank bajaj finance etc
will keep on growing at 20 25 percent
say bajaj finance has a one and a half
percent market share or a quarter bank
has a one and a half percent market
share will they go to
three percent four percent market share
or not that is the only question
uh that needs to be uh that needs to be
thought about
irrespective of what the price to book
multiple is as long as you have a longer
time horizon
uh you like you'll have share price
performance which will be
similar to your book value per share
compounding so let's assume that
let's assume that over the next five
years book value per share compounding
for these companies is twenty percent
um in case you enter you would have
entered
before covet or say in march april may
or
uh price your share price compounding
would have been 21 22
if you enter now maybe it will be 18 19
or it might be 20 21
but the impact of entry price to book
multiples is not significant over a long
period of time
so so jen it's not too late whether it's
ccp kcp we have consistently
helped clients understand demonstrated
that there is no right or wrong time to
integrate franchises uh
if you haven't invested in kcv reach out
to our
marcellus representative or if you're
coming by a wealth manager reach out to
the wealth manager
as deepak gupta no less explained
we're in the early stages of what looks
like an economic recovery
and whilst we can all sit here worrying
about inflation second wave third wave
if you want to participate in the
economic recovery
this is a good time to invest leaving
aside whatever happens to macro
a stage explained right at the outset
there are three layers of upside that we
get to play
over the next two three four years the
first is the improvement in earnings
earning improvement in credit quality as
the kovit
as the kovitz care abates economy
normalizes credit quality improves all
of us will benefit from that the
earnings the profits of these
lenders will benefit from that
secondly uh we benefit from the
improvement in credit growth right
explained that in sectors like housing
finance there's much less competition
now for the champion lenders than there
was
two three years ago four years ago many
of the uh
housing finance companies who were there
were two who were
posing competition two three years ago
have flamed out and therefore
for well-run lenders there's plenty of
opportunity and the third layer is
the pe multiple normalizing from that
massive scare that
it received the lending sector received
last year so you're playing three layers
of upside
uh uh and therefore it's not too late to
enter the kcp portfolio
there's one last question and we'll then
draw things to a close
anurag shukla says with unsecured retail
under stress where does that leave bajaj
finance stage
yeah sure so uh bajaj finance
right now has about 26 year one
this is after providing for very
aggressively
at the beginning of kovit itself last
march itself
they said that they'll provide for about
six to seven percent of their loan book
uh they already provided for four five
percent the remaining one one and a half
percent will come through in the
uh last quarter despite all of this
despite all of this their return on
equity for this year
has been thirteen fourteen percent uh
and this is a year with co-ed
now next year uh they'll go back to
twenty percent plus
return on equity and this is assuming
that whatever they provided for
is uh is going to be completely written
off
they've themselves uh themselves
provided for aggressively
uh in their assessment uh and what
has come about of uh their unsecured
loan book
is much much better than most of the
estimates
that were made in much april may last
year
uh secondly when we look at their loan
book
about 55 to 60 percent is not unsecured
uh this is
uh there is this policy that bad finance
runs are completely unsecured long book
about 35 of it is housing finance more
than a third of their loan book is
housing finance
about 10 to 15 percent is uh auto loans
which is lending to the bajaj auto uh
customers
and then there is 10 15 20 which is sme
and
other sorts of secured lending so less
than half of their loan book is
unsecured and even on that they've
aggressively provided for
despite this aggressive provision
they're at more than 25
tier one very well positioned for uh the
sort of growth that will come about
and especially in the unsecured space
because most lenders have seen that
what's happened through kovid in
unsecured lending space
it has completely damaged their loan
book most of them
are exiting or have already exited this
space that leaves
wide by the ground wide open or bajaj
finance to accelerate
so uh i'll take one last question and
then we'll uh
draw the curtain on today's show so
although
says that look i've already invested in
ccp if i invest in kcp won't i just be
you know duplicating the portfolio
no sir you won't be there's only a four
stock overlap
between ccp and kcp uh the fourth ccp
land the four ccp financial services
stocks are also in
kings of capital kings of capital has a
further eight stocks
which are not part of consistent
compounders and therefore you get
a completely new type of compounding
driven on the back of lending
insurance asset management and wealth
management in our country
so so thank you folks thank you for your
questions uh uh thank you for joining us
today
as we spoke to one of the domains of
indian banking deepak gupta
thanks a lot bye for now thanks stage
thank you thanks lord of thanks